Guide to the James Lippincott Goodwin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association "old" correspondence, 1920-1949; Series II
  - Conservation Corps Work, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Outline of proposed work for Co-operative Association under National Recovery Administration.
  - D, 1925-1936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Correspondence with members of the Association relative to payment of dues, survey work and membership period.
  - Data and Correspondence, Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Revised 1935 Constitution of the Association; Association Membership Lists, 1944 and 1948; Comparative Financial Statement, 1944; 1951-1953 Schedule and repayment of loans to J. L. Goodwin; Bulletins regarding fighting of forest fires and combatting the Gypsy Moth.
  - E, 1923-1939 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    File card of members showing length of membership in the Association; Correspondence between James L. Goodwin and members of the Association concerning such areas as clear-cutting their land, employment of Association personnel for forestry work and requests for land mapping.
  - Ellsworth, John S., Survey-Timber Estimates, 1924-1937 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Correspondence with James L. Goodwin concerning land and timber survey commissioned by Mr. Ellsworth.
  - Ensign-Bickford Company, Survey, 1925-1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Correspondence is between James L. Goodwin, S. W. Eddy and J. R. Ensign regarding accurate map survey of forest property of the Avon plant.
  - F, 1925-1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    This folder in addition to the correspondence between James L. Goodwin and the membership includes file cards on duration of Membership in the Association, list of Fire Wardens of the Town of Simsbury in 1939; Price list of transplants from the Experimental Station and correspondence with the American Forestry Association regarding the James Montgomery Flagg Fire Prevention Stamp.
  - Forest Protective Associations, Connecticut, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Correspondence concerns an exchange of information between the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association and the following Protective Associations: Naugatuck Valley, Central Fairfield County and High Rock.
  - Forest Surveying Applications for Jobs, 1936, 1939-1943 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Tabulation of work hours, dates and charges to members of the Association.
  - Furlong, Frank P., 1920-1943 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Correspondence between Association member Furlong and Mr. Goodwin concerns survey and forestry assignments on the Furlong property as well as a Deed and Description in the Chain of Title to the Furlong property from 1888 to 1920.
  - G, 1929-1938 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Correspondence between Mr. Goodwin and various members of the Association with respect to routine Association business.
  - H, 1924-1934 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Correspondence is of routine Association business and includes communication with the Hartford Girl Scouts and work assignments for their Hartland property.
  - Hawes, Austin, State Forester, 1923-1931 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Correspondence between Mr. Hawes and Mr. Goodwin regarding timber purchase agreements between Connecticut and the Association, data on owners and tracts sold to the State at Peoples Forest, Barkhampsted; Agreement between Connecticut and the Association and a summary of Forestry Unemployment Project of 1931.
  - Hawes, Austin, State Forester, 1931-1940 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Agreement between the State and certain members of the Association to allow the State Forestry Department permission to mark off one-acre plot for a five-year growth study; 1933 Listing of the seven Connecticut Forestry Protective Associations and their officers; 1937 proposal to limit clear-cutting by Association members; Report of the work of the Civilian Conservation Corps in Connecticut.
  - Illick, Professor Joseph, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    These two letters between Professor of Forest Management Illick of Syracuse University and Mr. Goodwin recapitulate the history of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association.
  - Insurance, 1937-1944 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Workman's Compensation records and the Statements of Audit Adjustments for the Hartford Accident and Indemity Company and Allen, Russell and Allen Insurance.
  - K, 1929-1943 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Correspondence with Kellogg and Bulkeley Company regarding lithography of Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association maps; Henri Kieffer, Chief Forest Protection Service, Quebec, seeking information; Congressional Representative Herman P. Kopplemann regarding opposition to the proposed legislation of placing the Forest Service in the Department of the Interior.
  - Keene Forestry Association, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Correspondence and invoice for 100 White Pine transplants sold to Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association.
  - L, 1931-1939 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Correspondence between H. Lathrop, Assistant State Forest Fire Warden and Mr. Goodwin; Exchange of information about Association business with Litchfield Forestry Association; Report from United States Senator Augustine Lonergan concerning appropriations for the Clark McNary Law for fire prevention.
  - Lists of Members, 1924-1941 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Membership lists indicating member, number on map, number of acres and location of property from November, 1924 to April, 1941.
  - M, 1924-1940 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Correspondence with members of the Association including member, George P. McLean, United States Senator, concerning patrolling, forestry work and assessment of property.
  - Membership, Clear-cut Restriction Slips, 1938-1946 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    These pink slips from the membership reflect the Connecticut State stipulation that the member agree not to practice clear-cutting except for up to three acres of land or land needed for a road or for reservoir purposes.
  - Metropolitan District Commission, 1924-1940 (Box 7, Folder 30a)
    Correspondence between Caleb Saville, Manager and Chief Engineer and Mr. Goodwin regarding the Metropolitan District Commission's membership in the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association including fire Preventive measures, dues, land coverage and concern over state control of the Association.
  - N, 1924-1938 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Correspondence urging the New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company to plow fire lines and practice preventative measures as well as correspondence with a job applicant and file cards showing duration of membership.
  - O, 1929-1940 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    File cards of members: Letters from James Goodwin to the Editor of the Outlook, in defense of the Forest Service.
  - P, 1927-1940 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    This folder contains file cards showing length of Association membership; 1928 List of Fire Protective Associations and general correspondence with memberships.
  - Peoples Forest, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 33a)
    A letter to Dr. T. Chester from Mr. Goodwin regarding Survey of Peoples Forest for the State Forestry Department.
  - Pine Plantations and Plantings, 1929-1933 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Tabulations of pine planting by member, tree, age of tree, year and cost.
  - Planting, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    Tabulations of tree planting by member, tree, age of tree, year and cost.
  - Planting, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Planting, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 36a)
    Tabulations of tree planting.
  - Planting, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    Tabulation of tree planting by member, tree, age of tree, year and cost.
  - Planting, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    Tabulations of tree planting by member, tree age of tree, year and cost; Orders of the Keene Forestry Association, New Hampshire.
  - Planting, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Planting, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Planting, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    Tabulations of tree planting by member, tree, age of tree, year and cost; Orders for trees from Association members.
  - Planting, Fall, 1941- Spring, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    Planting orders of Association members ordering from various nurseries and the Connecticut Agricultural Station.
  - Planting, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    Planting orders of Association members.
  - Planting, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    Planting of pine trees of Association members in 1944; Planting stock from Great Pond Inventory, and a tabulation of membership tree ownership whether it be white pine, red pine, Norway spruce or white spruce giving planting dates from 1930 to 1941.
  - Planting, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    Orders from members of the Association; Price lists from the Talcott Mountain Forest Association and the Connecticut State Park and Park Commission.
  - Planting, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    Tabulation of tree planting, 1946.
  - Planting, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    Tabulation of tree planting, 1947; Individual order forms and Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association price list.
  - Planting, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    Tabulation of tree planting, 1948.
  - Planting, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    Tabulation of tree planting
  - R, 1923-1938 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    Correspondence with members and prospective members concerning the work of the Association; Correspondence with Louis Howe, Secretary to President Roosevelt regarding keeping the Forest Service in the Department of Agriculture.
  - Receipted Bills, 1925-1936 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    Random number of paid bills to such companies as the Scioto Sign Company, Douglas Pump Company and American Fire Equipment Company, Incorporated for fire prevention signs and fire-fighting equipment.
  - Receipted Bills, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    Paid Bills to forestry workers and Keene Forestry Association for forestry stock.
  - Receipted Bills, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Receipted Bills, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Record of the Expenses and Advancements by the State of Connecticut to Forest Patrolmen Weed and Tuller.
  - Receipted Bills, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    Record of the Expenses and Advancements by the State of Connecticut Forestry Department; Weekly Labor Reports for Forest Patrolmen Weed and Tuller.
  - Receipted Bills, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    Record of the Expenses and Advancements by the State of Connecticut; Connecticut Weekly Labor Reports for Forest Patrolmen Weed and Tuller.
  - Receipted Bills, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Receipted Bills, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    Talcott Mountain Patrolmen Monthly Reports for H. N. Ebert and F. J. Emigh.
  - Reo Truck and Fire Equipment, 1925, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    Order form and insurance notice for this truck.
  - Reports, Financial, Annual, Secretary's, 1923-1941 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    Financial Reports of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association giving expenditures, receipts and reimbursement by the State of Connecticut for the work of the Patrolmen. There are Minutes of Annual Meetings from 1923 to 1927.
  - Report to Members, 1938-1964 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    Reports to the Membership concern the calls to Annual Meeting, directives about the limitation on clear-cutting forest land, control of gypsy moth infestation, membership lists and the 1959 decision to expand services of the Association.
  - Quarterly Changes, 1936-1947 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    Lists of members and acreage added or withdrawn from the Association.
  - Quarterly Reports, 1944-1947, 1948-1933 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    Two binders contain Quarterly Reports presented by dames L. Goodwin, Secretary and Treasurer.
  - S, 1929-1939 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    File cards of membership and correspondence with members, especially Herbert Knox Smith, about such subjects as surveying, hiring extra patrol people, purchase of fire-equipment and furnishing of pine transplants.
  - Social Security and Income Tax Withheld, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    Withholding Exemption Certificates, Payroll Deductions and Employer's Tax Returns.
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    Withholding Statements, Employer's Tax Return and Payroll Deduction slips.
  - Stocking, Edson, R. F. D. Avon, Connecticut, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    Covering letter of Mr. Stocking's on membership.
  - Timber Estimates, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    Records on the Timber Estimate for John S. Ellsworth of Simsbury, Connecticut.
  - U, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    There is one letter from the United States Department of Agriculture stating that the Forestry Service will not be removed from the Department of Agriculture.
  - V, 1924-1937 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    Correspondence mainly with Member Curtis Veeder regarding trespassing, clear-cutting and purchase of seedlings for the Membership.
  - Victory and Withholding Taxes, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    Victory and Withholding Taxes for Vernon Tuller, William Weed and Francis Emigh.
  - W, 1926-1934 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    Correspondence concerns fire-fighting equipment, membership in the Association and correspondence with United States Senator Walcott regarding keeping the Forestry Department in the Department of Agriculture.
  - Yale Forestry School, 1925-1930 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    Correspondence between James L. Goodwin and Professor Henry Graves and School of Forestry Librarian, Francis Bolton, acknowledges receipt of Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association Reports.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association-Account Books: 1924-1930 1930-1941, 1941-1952, The Phoenix Bank and Trust Company. (Box 10)
- Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association "New" Correspondence, 1924-1955; Series III
  - A, 1945-1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Allen, Russell and Allen Insurance Agents for the Association; Bills, Statements of Audit Adjustment for Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company; File cards of members.
  - B, 1939-1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Correspondence between Association members and J. L. Goodwin regarding surveys of property, and all matters relating to the Association; Care of property; File cards of members.
  - C, 1936-1955 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    File cards of members; J. L. Goodwin concern with purchase equipment for the Association and dues collection.
  - Circular letters, 1924-1925, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 3a)
    Secretary Goodwin corresponding with Association members on such subjects as map survey, timber estimate and evaluation, fire control, reforestation; Revised 1935 Constitution.
  - D, 1936-1953 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    File cards of members.
  - E, 1942-1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    J. L. Goodwin correspondence with Association members about tax refund for hurricane damage and ice-storm damage; File cards of members.
  - F, 1945-1955 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with Frank Furlong regarding list of men who were available for fire patrol; W. G. Fyler suggesting Association reorganization; File cards of members.
  - Filley, W. D. Connecticut Agriculture Station, 1941-1943 (Box 11, Folder 6a)
    Request for information.
  - G, 1941-1953 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with Association members about blight control, surveying, payment for Association services; J. L. Goodwin, Treasurer in 1953.
  - Gangell, Myles, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 7a)
    Correspondence with the Association patrolmen.
  - Gray, Robert, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 7b)
    Surveyor notes on New Hartford boundary dispute between Catholic Order and Robert Gray.
  - Gypsy Moth, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7c)
    News-clipping on the prevalence of the gypsy moth and control of it; Letters from Association members seeking assistance in spraying.
  - H, 1941-1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Routine Association business correspondence such as payment of patrolmen, work regulations and dues collection; File cards of members.
  - Hawes, A. F., State Forester, 1941-1948 (Box 11, Folder 8a)
    Contract between the State Park and Forest Commission and the Association for the sale of stumpage; appointments of patrolmen for the Talcott Mountain area.
  - I, 1937-1950 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Indian Fire Pump catalogues.
  - J, 1930-1939 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - K, 1944-1954 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    Correspondence with Dr. Raymond Kienholz, State Forester, regarding payment for services of patrolmen; File cards of members.
  - L, 1941-1955 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Routine Association business such as billing for dues and services; "L" file cards.
  - M, 1933-1955 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Routine Association business; News-clipping for 1947 forest fires; File cards for members.
  - Membership Co-Operative Agreements, 1937-1939 (Box 11, Folder 13a)
    Agreements between Connecticut State Forestry Department and Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association whereby forest fire protection is given the Association when the Association members agree to limit the number of acres cleared to three acres a year; 1937 and 1938 membership lists of those Association members agreeing to this provision.
  - Membership, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 13b)
    Association Bulletin stating fact of dues increase.
  - Membership List, 1940-1953 (Box 11, Folder 13c)
    Revised membership lists.
  - Miscellaneous, 1941-1943 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Membership slips agreeing to conservation requirements; News-clipping of Bristol Fire; Fire Prevention Poster.
  - N, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - O, 1948-1953 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Routine Association correspondence regarding dues collection and services by patrolmen.
  - P, 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association-Phoenix State Bank and Trust Company Deposit Book; Routine Association correspondence; Forestry student enquiries about employment.
  - Parker, S. E., District Forester, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 16a)
    Request for information about signs and employees; Association Constitution.
  - Pont, Clarence, Patrolman, 1943-1955 (Box 12, Folder 16b)
    Correspondence between Clarence Pont, Association Patrolman and J. L. Goodwin about patrolling, forestry work for members and collection of dues.
  - Planting Pines, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 16c)
    Association planting work sheets; Price lists and member orders.
  - Plants, Summary of Transplants, 1929-1948 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Tabulations: Membership transplants list, 1928-1948; Species of Trees planted, 1929-1948.
  - Q, 1943-1949 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Quebec Forestry Association correspondence with J. L. Goodwin; File cards of members.
  - R, 1934-1955 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Correspondence with membership about maintenance of property and dues collection; File cards of members.
  - Receipted Bills, 1947-1949 (Box 12, Folder 18a)
    Patrolman's weekly Report; Bills for maintenance.
  - Receipted Bills, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 18b)
    Assorted bills for maintenance.
  - Receipted Bills, 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 18c)
  - Replies to Talcott Mountain Protective Association letter, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Letters from Association members expressing interest in the future operation of the Association.
  - S, 1941-1954 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    orrespondence regarding routine Association business such as billing for dues, ordering of trees, and forestry work; File cards of members.
  - Scioto Sign Company, 1925-1952 (Box 12, Folder 19a)
    Invoices and bills for "No Trespassing" signs.
  - Social Security, 1937-1945 (Box 12, Folder 19b)
    Social Security Work sheets; Employers Tax Return Form; Correspondence with the Commissioner of Internal Revenue about collection of back taxes for patrolmen.
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 19c)
    Records of wages and Social Security for patrolmen; Summary of year's wages; Payroll deduction slips.
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Tax records.
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 19e)
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Social Security and Income Taxes, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 19g)
  - Statements, Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1924, 1925, 1930-1945 (Box 13, Folder 19h)
    Financial Statements: Quarterly and Annual Statements of expenditures and receipts; Treasurer's Report, Comparative Statement; Membership.
  - Statement of Connecticut Reports, 1942-1949 (Box 13, Folder 19i)
    Correspondence between A. F. Hawes, State Forester and J. L. Goodwin about the Agreement between the State Forestry Department and the Association with an itemized list of Department expenditures for fire protection.
  - T, 1929-1955 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    Membership list of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association; File cards of members.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1935-1948 (Box 13, Folder 20a)
    Table of Expenditures; List of unpaid members; List of paid members; 1935 Constitution.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1945-1959 (Box 13, Folder 20b)
    1945 List of Itemized expenditures; Summary of membership change; 1945-1948 Statement of Fire Protection receipts and expenditures.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 20c)
    Summary of membership change; Statement of expenditures, July 1, 1949-June 30, 1950.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    Summary of membership change; 1951 payroll.
  - Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 20e)
    Membership lists, 1951-1952.
  - U, 1943-1954 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    United States Treasury Department correspondence includes Annual Return and Exemption Forms.
  - V, 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    Routine Association business correspondence.
  - W, 1924-1944 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    List of available fire wardens, 1942.
  - Water Board, Metropolitan District, Commission, 1941-1943 (Box 13, Folder 23a)
    Correspondence between Careb Mills Saville, Manager and Chief Engineer of the Commission and J. L. Goodwin regarding the Commission's membership in the Association and the use by the Commission of patrolmen for guarding reservoirs.
  - Weed, William B, Patrolman, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 23b)
    Correspondence regarding Mr. Weed's work in collecting dues, patrolling, doing forestry work, and purchasing equipment for the Association.
  - Cord Wood Cuttings, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 23c)
    Replies by members of the Association to the Circular Letter suggesting method of cutting and distribution of cord wood in consideration of fuel shortage.
  - Cord Wood Cutting, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    Circular Letter replies regarding fuel shortage.
  - Y, 1940-1944 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    Routine Association business.
  - Z, 1935-1945 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    Routine Association business and File cards of members.
- Carthage Plantation Correspondence, 1927-1959; Series IV
  - Book-keeping, 1927-1942 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Original Book Entries for roads and paths, 1928-1942; Entries: survey maps, forestry maintenance, taxes, forestry overhead, care of property by Colin G. Spencer, 1927-1942; Original timber and cordwood entries, 1927-1942.
  - Book-keeping, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Forest Industries Schedule, Bureau of Internal Revenue; Operating Expenses and receipts, 1934-1944; Timber survey work sheet, 1942; Analysis of maintenance accounts, 1943; Correspondence between James L. Goodwin and Professor Walter Meyer, Yale School of Forestry stating opinion of Income Tax Ruling affecting Mr. Goodwin's North Carolina timber property, 1943-1944.
  - Booklets culled from Carthage file (Box 14, Folder 2a)
    "Better Seed for Better Southern Forests", "A Ten Year Master Forestry Program for the North Carolina Forest Service as proposed by the Division of Forestry".
  - Books and Taxes, 1940-1944 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Worksheets of Carthage Forestry; Analysis of Maintenance accounts.
  - Dowd Piece, 1927-1930 (Box 14, Folder 4)